let questions = [
    {
    numb: 1,
    question: "In which of the following inscriptions Ashoka made his famous declaration, All men are my children?",
    answer: "Separate Kalinga Rock Edict I",
    options: [
      "Minor Rock Edict",
      "Pillar Edict VII",
      "Lumbini Pillar Edict",
      "Separate Kalinga Rock Edict I"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 2,
    question: "Which of the following Rigvedic deities represented Storm?",
    answer: "Maruts",
    options: [
      "Indra",
      "Maruts",
      "Varun",
      "Apas"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 3,
    question: "The achievements of which ruler was recorded in Nasik Inscription?",
    answer: "Gautamiputra Satkarni",
    options: [
      "Ashoka",
      "Bindusara",
      "Devabhummi",
      "Gautamiputra Satkarni"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 4,
    question: "Which of the following passes was used by Sakas to come to India?",
    answer: "Bolan Pass",
    options: [
      "Bolan Pass",
      "Nathu La Pass",
      "Shipki La Pass",
      "Bara-lacha la Pass"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 5,
    question: "Allahabad Pillar Inscription gives a detailed account of the reign of which of the following?",
    answer: "Samudra gupta",
    options: [
      "Kanishka",
      "Samudra gupta",
      "Kumaragupta",
      "Ashoka"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "What was the capital of the southern part of Avanti Mahajanapada?",
    answer: "Mahishmati",
    options: [
      "Mahishmati",
      "Mathura",
      "Ujjain",
      "Taxila"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 7,
    question: "In which century the first punched marked coins were used?",
    answer: "6th century BCE",
    options: [
      "5th century BCE",
      "7th century BCE",
      "8th century BCE",
      "6th century BCE"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 8,
    question: "Which of the following area was not surrendered to Chandragupta Maurya by Seleucus Nicator?",
    answer: "Northern Afghanistan",
    options: [
      "Gandhara",
      "Kabul",
      "Herat",
      "Northern Afghanistan"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 9,
    question: "Which Rock Edict announces that the gift of Dhamma is the best gift of all gifts?",
    answer: "Eleventh Edict",
    options: [
      "Eighth Edict",
      "Ninth Edict",
      "Eleventh Edict",
      "Twelfth Edict"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 10,
    question: "What is the Upveda of  Samaveda called?",
    answer: "Gandhraveda ",
    options: [
      "Ayurveda",
      "Shilpaveda",
      "Gandhraveda ",
      "Dhanuraveda"
    ]
  },
];

